{
  "course": "MTS 105",
  "compiled_by": "GODSPEED AND HAY WHY OH",
  "sections": [
    {
      "section": "TRIGONOMETRY",
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "Which of the following is the correct value of cot 10°.cot 20°.cot 60°.cot 70°.cot 80°?",
          "options": {
            "a": "1/√3",
            "b": "√3",
            "c": "-1",
            "d": "1"
          },
          "answer": "a"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "If a sin 45° = b cosec 30°, what is the value of a⁴/b⁴?",
          "options": {
            "a": "63",
            "b": "43",
            "c": "23",
            "d": "None of the above"
          },
          "answer": "a"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "If tan θ + cot θ = 2, then what is the value of tan¹⁰⁰ θ + cot¹⁰⁰ θ?",
          "options": {
            "a": "1",
            "b": "3",
            "c": "2",
            "d": "None of the above"
          },
          "answer": "c"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "If the value of α + β = 90°, and α: β = 2: 1, then what is the ratio of cos α to cos β?",
          "options": {
            "a": "1: 3",
            "b": "√3: 1",
            "c": "1: √3",
            "d": "None of the above"
          },
          "answer": "b"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "If θ is said to be an acute angle, and 7 sin² θ + 3 cos² θ = 4, then what is the value of tan θ?",
          "options": {
            "a": "1",
            "b": "√3",
            "c": "1/√3",
            "d": "None of the above"
          },
          "answer": "c"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "If tan θ - cot θ = 0, what will be the value of sin θ + cos θ?",
          "options": {
            "a": "1",
            "b": "√2",
            "c": "1/√2",
            "d": "None of the above"
          },
          "answer": "b"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "If θ is said to be an acute angle, and 4 cos² θ - 1 = 0, then what is the value of tan (θ - 15°)?",
          "options": {
            "a": "1",
            "b": "√2",
            "c": "1/√3",
            "d": "None of the above"
          },
          "answer": "c"
        },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question": "If the value of θ + φ = π/2, and sin θ = 1/2, what will be the value of sinφ?",
          "options": {
            "a": "1",
            "b": "√2",
            "c": "√3/2",
            "d": "2/√3"
          },
          "answer": "c"
        },
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question": "What will be the value of 2cos² θ - 1, if cos⁴ θ - sin⁴ θ = 2/3?",
          "options": {
            "a": "1",
            "b": "2",
            "c": "3/2",
            "d": "2/3"
          },
          "answer": "d"
        },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question": "What will be the value of 1 - 2sin² θ, if cos⁴ θ - sin⁴ θ = 2/3?",
          "options": {
            "a": "1",
            "b": "2",
            "c": "3/2",
            "d": "2/3"
          },
          "answer": "d"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "section": "POLYNOMIALS",
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "If one zero of the quadratic polynomial x² + 3x + k is 2, then the value of k is",
          "options": {
            "a": "10",
            "b": "-10",
            "c": "5",
            "d": "-5"
          },
          "answer": "b"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "A quadratic polynomial, whose zeroes are -3 and 4, is",
          "options": {
            "a": "x² - x + 12",
            "b": "x² + x + 12",
            "c": "x²/2 - x/2 - 6",
            "d": "2x² + 2x - 24"
          },
          "answer": "d"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "If the zeroes of the quadratic polynomial x² + (a + 1)x + b are 2 and -3, then",
          "options": {
            "a": "a = -7, b = -1",
            "b": "a = 5, b = -1",
            "c": "a = 2, b = -6",
            "d": "a = 0, b = -6"
          },
          "answer": "a"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "The number of polynomials having zeroes as -2 and 5 is",
          "options": {
            "a": "1",
            "b": "2",
            "c": "3",
            "d": "More than 3"
          },
          "answer": "d"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "If one of the zeroes of the cubic polynomial x³ + ax² + bx + c is -1, then the product of the other two zeroes is",
          "options": {
            "a": "b - a + 1",
            "b": "b - a - 1",
            "c": "a - b + 1",
            "d": "a - b - 1"
          },
          "answer": "a"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "The zeroes of the quadratic polynomial x² + 99x + 127 are",
          "options": {
            "a": "Both positive",
            "b": "Both negative",
            "c": "One positive and one negative",
            "d": "Both equal"
          },
          "answer": "b"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "The zeroes of the quadratic polynomial x² + kx + k, k ≠ 0,",
          "options": {
            "a": "Cannot both be positive",
            "b": "Cannot both be negative",
            "c": "Are always unequal",
            "d": "Are always equal"
          },
          "answer": "a"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "section": "MATRICES",
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "The value of x, for which the matrix A is singular is",
          "options": {
            "a": "9",
            "b": "8",
            "c": "7",
            "d": "6"
          },
          "answer": "c"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "If the points (x, -2), (5, 2), (8, 8) are collinear, then x is equal to",
          "options": {
            "a": "-3",
            "b": "1/3",
            "c": "1",
            "d": "3"
          },
          "answer": "d"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "If = abc/2 ≠ 0, then the area of the triangle whose vertices are is",
          "options": {
            "a": "1/4",
            "b": "1/4abc",
            "c": "1/8",
            "d": "1/8 abc"
          },
          "answer": "d"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "If the square of the matrix is the unit matrix of order 2, then α, β and γ should satisfy the relation.",
          "options": {
            "a": "1 + α² + βγ = 0",
            "b": "1 - α² - βγ = 0",
            "c": "1 - α² + βγ = 0",
            "d": "1 + α² - βγ = 0"
          },
          "answer": "b"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "A root of the equation = 0 is",
          "options": {
            "a": "6",
            "b": "3",
            "c": "0",
            "d": "-6"
          },
          "answer": "c"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "The value of the determinant of A is",
          "options": {
            "a": "-2abc",
            "b": "abc",
            "c": "0",
            "d": "a² + b² + c²"
          },
          "answer": "c"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "If x₁, x₂, x₃ as well as y₁, y₂, y₃ are in geometric progression with the same common ratio, then the points (x₁, y₁), (x₂, y₂), (x₃, y₃) are",
          "options": {
            "a": "vertices of an equilateral triangle",
            "b": "vertices of a right angled triangle",
            "c": "vertices of a right angled isosceles triangle",
            "d": "collinear"
          },
          "answer": "d"
        },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question": "If a ≠ b, b, c satisfy = 0, then abc =",
          "options": {
            "a": "a + b + c",
            "b": "0",
            "c": "b³",
            "d": "ab + bc"
          },
          "answer": "b"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}